<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; Staging ALLHC</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../index.html</link>
	<description>Ayalaland Logistics Holdings Corp.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:43:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../wp-content/uploads/2024/09/favicon-300x300-1.png</url>
	<title>News &#8211; Staging ALLHC</title>
	<link>./../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>VSIP signs lease with ALLHC for 52,7000 sqm space at ALogis Santo Tomas – marking first Philippine address</title>
		<link>./../vsip-signs-lease-with-allhc-for-527000-sqm-space-at-alogis-santo-tomas-marking-first-philippine-address/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[fligno_dev]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 07:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../index.html?post_type=news#038;p=4021</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC) announces a new collaboration with VS Industry Philippines, Inc. (VSIP), a wholly owned subsidiary of Malaysia’s leading …]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC) announces a new collaboration with VS Industry Philippines, Inc. (VSIP), a wholly owned subsidiary of Malaysia’s leading Electronics Manufacturing Services (EMS) provider, VS Industry Berhad (VS). VSIP will occupy over 52,700 sqm of gross leasable space in ALogis Santo Tomas, marking their first operational address in the Philippines and their initial partnership with ALLHC.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>VS delivers vertically integrated manufacturing solutions to global multinational corporations, serving as both an Original Equipment Manufacturer (OEM) and an Original Design Manufacturer (ODM). Its services span high-precision printed circuit board assembly, plastic injection molding, full and sub-assembly, as well as tool design and fabrication.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>With its expansion in the Philippines through VSIP, the group is set to fulfill new orders from a key customer, focusing on the box-build assembly of consumer electronics. This comprehensive service covers the entire process from production to assembly, testing, packaging, labeling, and logistics, reinforcing VSIP’s commitment to excellence and meeting growing market demands.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Covering a leasable area of 52,700 sqm within ALogis Santo Tomas, the facility is slated for turnover within Q3 2024, with mass production set to begin by Q2 2025 and employing a workforce of approximately 2,000 people upon completion.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Situated in Santo Tomas, Batangas, this PEZA-accredited facility is easily accessible from Manila via the South Luzon Expressway (SLEX) and from Batangas City via the Southern Tagalog Arterial Road (STAR).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>VS Managing Director Datuk S.Y. Gan emphasizes, “After careful consideration, we selected ALogis Santo Tomas as our manufacturing base in the Philippines due to its strategic location and accessibility. ALLHC provided invaluable support and expertise throughout the process. This is crucial for VS as this is a new venture for us and it also forms part of our asset-light model as a core element of our risk management strategy. All in all, we are thrilled to partner with one of the country’s leading industrial real estate companies and we are confident in our plans in the Philippines as we embark on a new chapter of growth.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“We are grateful to VS Industry Philippines, Inc. for selecting ALogis Santo Tomas as their initial base of operations in the country. As we look forward to serving VSIP as one of our valued tenants, we remain committed to our shared mission of positively impacting the local economy through job creation and encouraging further investment in the region. Indeed, we are confident that this strategic partnership will be both productive and beneficial,” shares ALLHC President and CEO Robert S. Lao.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>With this landmark collaboration, ALLHC and VSIP are set to contribute significantly to local economic growth and employment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ALLHC expands cold storage network with a new facility in Cebu</title>
		<link>./../4023-2/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[fligno_dev]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 07:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../index.html?post_type=news#038;p=4023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC) breaks ground for the construction of ALogis Artico Consolacion. Strategically located to meet the increasing demand for …]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC) breaks ground for the construction of ALogis Artico Consolacion. Strategically located to meet the increasing demand for temperature-controlled facilities in the Central Visayas region, the new facility will add 6,000 pallet positions to ALLHC’s cold storage portfolio. This will be ALLHC’s second facility in the province of Cebu following the addition of ALogis Artico Mandaue in late 2022.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The firm is expanding its cold storage footprint, aiming to provide solutions for storing perishable goods around the country. Aiming to cater to diverse sectors, its intended clientele varies from the frozen meat, seafood, pharmaceutical, and chemical industries, among others.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>During the first half of 2024, ALLHC opened its 4<sup>th</sup> cold storage facility, ALogis Artico Santo Tomas in Batangas. Now, ALLHC is furthering its growth by enhancing its presence in Cebu with the Consolacion site slated for completion by Q3 2025.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Situated in Brgy. Tayud, Consolacion, Cebu, the facility is easily accessible via the Cebu-North Coastal Road and is in close proximity to key transportation hubs, including the Mactan-Cebu International Airport and Cebu Port—both just 12 kilometers or a 30-minute drive away. ALogis Artico Consolacion will be equipped with 16 cold rooms with temperatures ranging from 5°C to -25°C; one processing room; and a capacity of 6,000 pallet positions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>ALogis Artico Consolacion will be registered with the Board of Investments (BOI), the National Meat Inspection Service (NMIS), the Bureau of Fisheries and Aquatic Resources (BFAR), and the Bureau of Plant Industry (BPI). These registrations ensure that the facility will meet stringent industry standards for food safety and quality.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>NMIS Regional Director Dr. Alvin A. Leal looks forward to the completion of the facility stating, “<em>I consider Cebu as an economic hub that distributes meat products outside of Cebu going to Mindanao and the adjacent provinces of Cebu. This facility can really help us in our desire and our implementation to produce sound, safe meat for the meat-consuming public.</em>”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“<em>I am so thankful that ALLHC are true, good partners. This is the second facility they have established in Cebu, and they are just right on time. The population of Cebu is tremendously multiplying. Within five years, it is going to double. Logistics is very important, and I do hope that with the opening of this facility, this will lead to more investments that will be complementing the needs of the people,</em>” adds Municipal Mayor Teresa P. Alegado.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>ALLHC Chief Operating Officer Patrick C. Avila shares, “<em>Our focus is on meeting the rising demand for dependable modern cold storage solutions, which are vital for the preservation of the quality of perishable goods to reduce food waste and post-harvest losses. By investing in this facility, we are not only broadening our capabilities, but also ensuring that we can provide our clients with various locations that can meet their needs.</em>”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ALLHC 1H24 net income up by 22% to P413M</title>
		<link>./../allhc-1h24-net-income-up-by-22-to-p413m/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[fligno_dev]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 07:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../index.html?post_type=news#038;p=4025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ALLHC delivered solid operational results in the first six months of 2024, posting consolidated revenues of P2.6 billion and net income of P413 million.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC), an Ayala Land, Inc. (ALI) subsidiary, delivered solid operational results in the first six months of 2024, posting consolidated revenues of P2.6 billion and net income of P413 million.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Revenues from the sale of industrial lots registered at P1.7 billion, reflecting healthy demand from locators. This was driven by lot sales at Laguindingan Technopark and higher completion rates for developing industrial estates.  Improvement in overall occupancy coupled with an increase in leasable area helped boost warehouse leasing revenues, rising 14% to P379 million from P331 million. Cold storage revenues totaled P92 million, an 8% increase versus last year, on account of contributions from the addition of ALogis Artico Santo Tomas and higher average rent. Meanwhile, revenues from commercial leasing registered at P466 million, up by 5% from improved mall occupancies.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“<em>Our first half performance exhibits our focus on achieving operational improvements across all core businesses this year</em>,” said ALLHC President and Chief Executive Officer Robert S. Lao. “<em>Alongside robust market activity, we believe our efforts to grow our asset portfolio and further enhance our industrial leasing segments will continue to position ALLHC well for growth for the remainder of 2024.</em>”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Last May, ALLHC delivered the 5,000-pallet position ALogis Artico Santo Tomas, its fourth cold storage facility, while in June, the company completed its first build-to-suit (BTS) project, a 15-000 sqm facility located within Cavite Technopark. Moreover, during the second quarter, ALLHC launched the second phase of its warehouse facilities in Pampanga Technopark, which will add 18,000 sqm of gross leasable area in the warehouse inventory upon delivery.</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>Also within Pampanga Technopark are projects that ALLHC expects to complete within the third quarter. The first phase of ALogis Mabalacat and the ALogis Artico Mabalacat cold storage will contribute 7,700 square meters of warehouse gross leasable area and 5,000 cold pallet positions, respectively.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In the same third quarter period, the company expects to break ground for its sixth and seventh cold storage facilities, ALogis Artico Santa Rosa in Laguna and ALogis Artico Consolacion in Cebu. Together, the two facilities will add 11,000 pallet positions to ALLHC’s expanding cold storage portfolio.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A-FLOW signs P2.4-billion Tranche 1 Loan of a P10.8-billion 10-Year Facility with LANDBANK</title>
		<link>./../a-flow-signs-p2-4-billion-tranche-1-loan-of-a-p10-8-billion-10-year-facility-with-landbank/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[fligno_dev]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 08:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../index.html?post_type=news#038;p=4026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A-FLOW Properties I Corp. (A-FLOW), a joint venture between AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC) and FLOW Digital Infrastructure, and Land Bank of the Philippines (LANDBANK) announced the signing of a P2.4 billion loan agreement representing Tranche 1 of a P10.8 billion 10-year loan.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A-FLOW Properties I Corp. (A-FLOW), a joint venture between Ayala Land, Inc. (ALI) subsidiary AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC) and FLOW Digital Infrastructure, and Land Bank of the Philippines (LANDBANK) announced the signing of a P2.4 billion loan agreement representing Tranche 1 of a P10.8 billion 10-year loan. The signing of the loan facility agreement underscores the mutual commitment to advancing the nation’s digital infrastructure and supporting the Philippines’ transition towards a more digitally integrated economy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The loan facility is intended for the development of the initial phase of the first A-FLOW data center campus located in Biñan, Laguna. Currently under construction, the 6MW-IT capacity Phase 1A of the three-building data center campus project is targeted to be ready-for-service by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A-FLOW President Amandine Wang said, “This agreement marks a significant step forward in our shared commitment to develop the largest carrier-neutral data center campus in the Philippines. We are excited to build an ecosystem to attract a combination of international hyperscale customers and local enterprise customers.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>LANDBANK President and CEO Ma. Lynette V. Ortiz emphasized the importance of collaborating with key stakeholders, “Beyond our work with various government agencies, we recognize that partnering with key players like A-FLOW is essential for advancing national development. In this era of rapid digitalization, we are likewise ready to drive investments into the local data center market, alongside other sectors contributing to our nation’s technological progress,” she said. Ortiz further commented, “This is the first data center project financed by LANDBANK, and with this new partnership, we are confident that this project will yield significant economic benefits.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For ALI President and CEO and ALLHC Chairman Anna Ma. Margarita B. Dy, digital transformation, cloud computing, and the rise of artificial intelligence are technologies that require robust and scalable data center solutions. “Ayala Land is proud to be participating in this new opportunity leveraging our land and our lucrative abilities to contribute to the country’s move towards a digital economy,” Dy said. “Like any other infrastructure project, capital is key. So, we thank LANDBANK for the P10.8 billion loan facility to A-FLOW, a critical enabler for this project,” she added.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A-FLOW’s partnership with LANDBANK enables both companies to capitalize on each other’s strengths, marking a shared vision of fostering innovation and sustainable growth. This milestone collaboration underscores the importance of public-private partnerships in serving the country and achieving the nation’s development goals.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Atkins expands operations in Cavite Technopark</title>
		<link>./../first-atkins-expands-operations-in-cavite-technopark/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[fligno_dev]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 07:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../index.html?post_type=news#038;p=4014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First Atkins Holdings Corp. (FAHC), the parent company of one of the leading figures in the wholesale and retail meat industry in the Philippines, has announced its significant expansion by acquiring additional lots within Cavite Technopark.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First Atkins Holdings Corp. (FAHC), the parent company of one of the leading figures in the wholesale and retail meat industry in the Philippines, has announced its significant expansion by acquiring additional lots within AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp.’s (ALLHC) Cavite Technopark. Launched in 2015, Cavite Technopark is ALLHC’s second industrial park in the bustling industrial corridor of the country, CALABARZON region. With its strategic location in Naic, Cavite, and close proximity to international gateways, including the Cavite Gateway Terminal and Sangley Airport, Cavite Technopark provides excellent accessibility and connectivity to businesses.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Leading Meat Supplier’s Increased Presence in CALABARZON Region</strong></p>
<p>FAHC is a key player in the Philippine meat industry, supplying major traditional and modern trade channels, hotels, restaurants, meat shops, commissaries, and meat traders across Luzon, and is further expanding its reach in the South of Metro Manila, Cavite, Laguna, and the rest of Region IV and Region V. Annually, they distribute over 120,000 metric tons (MT) of quality, affordable meat like pork, chicken, and beef. They are able to do so by utilizing a fleet of 150+ trucks and with a workforce of over 900 individuals.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Their facility within Cavite Technopark, officially inaugurated on March 2023, is one of the largest continuous cold storage warehouses (CSWs) in the Philippines and is the largest in South Luzon. The facility alone currently operates with a robust workforce of 180 individuals.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Emphasizing its commitment to sustainability, the facility incorporates renewable energy sources, boasting 1,078 solar panels contributing approximately 1MW of solar power. This augments the facility’s energy requirements and significantly reduces carbon emissions, aligning with broader environmental objectives.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“<em>We are delighted to welcome First Atkins Group’s expansion within Cavite Technopark,</em>” says Mr. Robert S. Lao, President and Chief Executive Officer of ALLHC. “<em>Choosing Cavite Technopark for their facility and upcoming expansion underscores our shared commitment to creating vibrant business environments that support growth and innovation.</em>”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Mr. Gabriel J. Ang, President &amp; CEO of FAHC, expressed that the company has considered Cavite Technopark’s advantageous location, especially with the upcoming Bataan – Cavite Interlink Bridge, which is set to revolutionize regional transportation, cutting travel time from four to five hours to 45 minutes. He conveyed enthusiasm about leveraging Cavite Technopark’s strategic benefits to further the company’s goal of delivering high-quality meat products to Filipino consumers. Additionally, he emphasized the importance of addressing market demand discrepancies and aligning with government food safety initiatives.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As the region’s leading meat supplier strengthens its presence, Cavite Technopark emerges as a dynamic hub driving economic progress and business excellence in South Luzon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AyalaLand Logistics opens Santo Tomas cold storage facility</title>
		<link>./../ayalaland-logistics-opens-santo-tomas-cold-storage-facility/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[fligno_dev]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 13:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../index.html?post_type=news#038;p=4112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From Business World   AYALALAND Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC) has opened its ALogis Artico Santo Tomas cold storage facility in Batangas. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="https://www.bworldonline.com/corporate/2024/05/16/595366/ayalaland-logistics-opens-santo-tomas-cold-storage-facility/">Business World</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p3">AYALALAND Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC) has opened its ALogis Artico Santo Tomas cold storage facility in Batangas.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p4">Formally opened on May 3, ALogis Artico Santo Tomas is the company’s first facility constructed from the ground up compared with previous facilities that were acquired, ALLHC said in an e-mailed statement on May 14.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p4">ALLHC is a subsidiary of listed property developer Ayala Land, Inc. (ALI).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p4">The new facility increases ALLHC’s existing cold storage portfolio by 5,000 pallet positions, expanding the company’s capacity to 15,300 pallet positions across four facilities. Additionally, the company operates cold storage facilities in Laguna and Cebu.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p4">Powered by renewable energy, ALogis Artico is equipped with 16 cold rooms featuring temperatures ranging from 5°C to -25°C. The facility caters to various clients such as frozen meat, seafood, and chemical industries.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p4">It is positioned within the Light Industry &amp; Science Park III in Sto. Tomas, Batangas, and addresses the surging demand for cold storage solutions in the South Luzon region.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p4">“We also aim to help address issues of food safety and security, and to support the country’s growing cold chain sector and its supply chain logistics. Moreover, we look forward to our latest development further energizing the city of Santo Tomas, and the whole of Batangas,” ALLHC President and Chief Executive Officer Robert S. Lao said.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p4"> ALI President and Chief Executive Officer Anna Ma. Margarita B. Dy said the company aims to achieve a consistent double-digit growth for the cold storage space in the next five years.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p4">“Using the strength of ALI’s strategically located landbank and financial stability, we aim to be a major player in the cold storage space,” she said.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p4">“The team has high aspirations on what we can do to be a major player in the industry, and in the process, contribute to the country’s goals of food security, and hopefully, also to bring down food prices as we improve distribution all around the country,” she added.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="p4">ALogis Artico Santo Tomas will be registered with key government agencies such as the Board of Investments, National Meat Inspection Service, Bureau of Fisheries and Aquatic Resources, and Bureau of Plant Industry to ensure adherence to regulatory standards. — <em><strong>Revin Mikhael D. Ochave</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ALLHC inaugurates ALogis Artico Santo Tomas</title>
		<link>./../allhc-inaugurates-alogis-artico-santo-tomas/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[fligno_dev]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 07:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../index.html?post_type=news#038;p=4015</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ALLHC recently celebrated the ceremonial opening of its latest facility, ALogis Artico Santo Tomas. This pivotal moment marks ALLHC’s first cold storage facility constructed from the ground up, distinguishing itself from the company's previous acquisitions.

]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC) recently celebrated a significant milestone with the ceremonial opening of its latest facility, ALogis Artico Santo Tomas. This pivotal moment marks ALLHC’s first cold storage facility constructed from the ground up, distinguishing itself from the company’s previous acquisitions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Adding 5,000 pallet positions to ALLHC’s existing cold storage portfolio, ALogis Artico Santo Tomas now bolsters the company’s capability to 15,300 pallet positions across four facilities. Equipped with 16 cold rooms featuring temperatures ranging from 5°C to -25°C and powered by renewable energy, the facility underscores ALLHC’s steadfast dedication to sustainable practices.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Strategically positioned within the Light Industry &amp; Science Park III in Sto. Tomas, Batangas, ALogis Artico Santo Tomas conveniently addresses the surging demand for cold storage solutions in the South Luzon region. Its proximity to Manila via the South Luzon Expressway (SLEX) and the Southern Tagalog Arterial Road (STAR Tollway) ensures accessibility, while the Batangas Port being just an hour’s drive away ensures efficient transportation of goods.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Robert S. Lao, President and CEO of ALLHC, expressed, “<em>We also aim to help address issues of food safety and security, and to support the country’s growing cold chain sector and its supply chain logistics. Moreover, we look forward to our latest development further energizing the city of Santo Tomas, and the whole of Batangas.</em>”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>To ensure adherence to regulatory standards, the facility will be registered with key authorities including the BOI (Board of Investments), NMIS (National Meat Inspection Service), BFAR (Bureau of Fisheries and Aquatic Resources), and BPI (Bureau of Plant Industry). Catering to clients from frozen meat, seafood, chemical industries, and beyond, ALogis Artico Santo Tomas is poised to become a key asset in the supply chain ecosystem.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“<em>We, at NMIS, support the establishment of this kind of facility that can follow standard. I believe the more we have accredited cold storages, the more sources we have of safe meat. This is our aspiration for the protection of the meat-consuming public</em>,” shared Dr. Fernando N. Lontoc, Director (Region 4A), National Meat Inspection Service.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Aileen P. Macapagal, Supervising Investments Specialist, Board of Investments stated, “<em>Food security is a top priority for the government, and the Board of Investments recognizes cold storage facilities as vital investments. These projects not only secure food for Filipino families but also generate jobs, having a transformative impact on our economy and national profile.</em>”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Anna Ma. Margarita B. Dy, President and CEO of Ayala Land, Inc. (ALI) and Chairman of ALLHC, shared, “<em>Using the strength of Ayala Land’s strategically located landbank and financial stability, we aim to be a major player in the cold storage space. As a relatively new player in the market, our intention is to achieve consistent double-digit growth for this business line in the next 5 years.</em>”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As the company continues to expand its footprint in the cold storage sector, it remains steadfast in its commitment to contributing meaningfully to food security and supply chain efficiency, aligning with broader national priorities. Ms. Dy adds, “<em>The team has high aspirations on what we can do to be a major player in the industry, and in the process, contribute to the country’s goals of food security, and hopefully, also to bring down food prices as we improve distribution all around the country.</em>”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tailored solutions for growing businesses</title>
		<link>./../tailored-solutions-for-growing-businesses/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[fligno_dev]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../index.html?post_type=news#038;p=4135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The build-to-suit facility underscores ALLHC's commitment to delivering real estate logistics solutions that cater to the needs of clients.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="https://www.manilatimes.net/2023/05/10/public-square/tailored-solutions-for-growing-businesses/1890704">Manila Times</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-6147" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/MRV02890.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="480" /></p>
<p>L-R: Patrick Avila, chief operating officer of ALLHC; Rainier Dominic Villanueva, business development associate manager of ALLHC; P. Ryan Isip, head of capital markets of JLL Philippines; Charlie McNaught, director for logistics and industrial of JLL Philippines; Justin David, general manager for new businesses of ALLHC; Rowena Tomeldan, chairman of Laguna Technopark Inc.; Francis Montojo, chief finance officer of ALLHC; and members Jessica Santos and Marita Cabral of the management committee of ALLHC</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>THE groundbreaking ceremony for AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp.’s (ALLHC) first build-to-suit facility in Cavite Technopark marks an important milestone for the company’s expansion.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The 15,000 square meters facility for a retailer is set to become the main distribution center for the nearby area, boasting over 30 loading bays, a concrete strength of 4,000 pounds per square inch, and a 9-meter clear height.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Expected to be completed by January 2024, the facility is set to provide employment opportunities for an estimated 300 workers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The build-to-suit facility underscores ALLHC’s commitment to delivering real estate logistics solutions that cater to the needs of clients.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AyalaLand Logistics net income up 18.5% in Q1, a reversal from 2023</title>
		<link>./../ayalaland-logistics-net-income-up-18-5-in-q1-a-reversal-from-2023/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[fligno_dev]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 06:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../index.html?post_type=news#038;p=4114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From Port Calls AyalaLand Logistics Holdings’ net income grew 18.5% year-on-year in the first quarter of the year to P211 million Consolidated ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="https://www.portcalls.com/ayalaland-logistics-net-income-up-18-5-in-q1-a-reversal-from-2023/">Port Calls</a></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h5><em><strong>AyalaLand Logistics Holdings’ net income grew 18.5% year-on-year in the first quarter of the year to P211 million</strong></em></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5><em><strong>Consolidated revenues of P1.3 billion jumped 85% to P1.3 billion for the same period in review</strong></em></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5><em><strong>Revenues from industrial lot sales remained steady</strong></em></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5><em><strong>Revenues from warehouse leasing and cold storage rose 15% and 3%, respectively</strong></em></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5><em><strong>For the second quarter, ALLHC expects to complete its first build-to-suit facility Cavite Technopark and the ALogis Mabalacat warehouse facility</strong></em></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5><em><strong>It will also open its ALogis Artico Santo Tomas and ALogis Artico Mabalacat cold storage facilities</strong></em></h5>
</li>
</ul>
<p>AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp.’s (ALLHC) net income grew 18.5% year-on-year in the first quarter of 2024 to P211 million from P178 million.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Consolidated revenues of P1.3 billion jumped 85% to P1.3 billion from P702 million for the same period in review.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The latest performance is a turnaround from the downturn experienced in 2023.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Demand for industrial lot sales remained steady, ALLHC in a statement, with revenue from industrial lot sales registering P851 million, mainly attributable to booked lot sales at Laguindingan Technopark paired with higher completion rates for industrial estates undergoing development works.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Revenue from warehouse leasing reached P175 million, a 15% increase year-on-year on account of higher overall occupancy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Cold storage ended the quarter with P41 million in revenues, up by 3% from last year.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Commercial leasing, meanwhile, posted revenues of P237 million, driven by improved mall occupancies and rental rates.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“ALLHC’s performance in the first quarter was promising and sets a positive tone for the year ahead,” ALLHC president and chief executive officer Robert Lao said in a<a href="https://www.ayalalandlogistics.com/press_releases/allhc-net-income-up-by-18-in-1q24/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> statement</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“Remaining focused on our expansion objectives, we are hopeful for the steady growth and progress of our businesses this year,” Lao added.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For the second quarter, ALLHC is expecting to complete its first build-to-suit facility in Cavite Technopark and the ALogis Mabalacat warehouse facility in Pampanga Technopark.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When completed, the two facilities will add 22,000 square meters (sqm) of warehouse gross leasable area.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>ALLHC is also set to open its ALogis Artico Santo Tomas and ALogis Artico Mabalacat cold storage facilities within the second quarter. Both facilities will add 5,000 pallet positions each to ALLHC’s cold storage portfolio.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Further, ALLHC will launch the second phase of its ALogis Mabalacat warehouse facility within the second quarter. The expansion is expected to add 18,000 sqm of gross leasable area in the warehouse portfolio upon delivery.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>ALLHC said all these projects are in line with the company’s direction to build up its asset portfolio and strengthen its leasing segment.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A subsidiary of Ayala Land, Inc., ALLHC has principal business interests in holding companies, commercial leasing, industrial lot sales and development, and retail electricity supply.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ALLHC net income up by 18% in 1Q24</title>
		<link>./../allhc-net-income-up-by-18-in-1q24/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[fligno_dev]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 07:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../index.html?post_type=news#038;p=4016</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ALLHC posted consolidated revenues of P1.3 billion and net income of P211 million in the first quarter of 2024, signaling a solid recovery from the downturn experienced in 2023.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AyalaLand Logistics Holdings Corp. (ALLHC), an Ayala Land, Inc. (ALI) subsidiary, posted consolidated revenues of P1.3 billion and net income of P211 million in the first quarter of 2024, signaling a solid recovery from the downturn experienced in 2023.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Demand for industrial lots remained steady with Industrial lot sales revenues registering at P851 million. This was mainly attributable to booked lot sales at Laguindingan Technopark paired with higher completion rates for industrial estates undergoing development works. Revenues from warehouse leasing reached P175 million, a 15% increase versus the same period last year, on account of higher overall occupancy. Cold storage ended the quarter with P41 million in revenues, up by 3% from last year. Meanwhile, commercial leasing posted revenues of P237 million, driven by improved mall occupancies and rental rates.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“<em>ALLHC’s performance in the first quarter was promising and sets a positive tone for the year ahead. With all core business lines showcasing notable improvements, we look forward to sustaining this growth momentum over the course of the year</em>,” said ALLHC President and Chief Executive Officer Robert S. Lao. “<em>Remaining focused on our expansion objectives, we are hopeful for the steady growth and progress of our businesses this year.</em>”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This second quarter, ALLHC is expecting to complete its first build-to-suit (BTS) facility in Cavite Technopark and the ALogis Mabalacat warehouse facility in Pampanga Technopark. Together, the two facilities will add 22,000 square meters of warehouse gross leasable area upon construction completion. ALLHC is also set to open its ALogis Artico Santo Tomas and ALogis Artico Mabalacat cold storage facilities within the period. Both facilities will add 5,000 pallet positions each to ALLHC’s portfolio.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Likewise, ALLHC will be launching the second phase of its ALogis Mabalacat warehouse facility within the second quarter. This expansion is expected to add 18,000 square meters of gross leasable area in the warehouse portfolio upon delivery.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>These projects are in line with the company’s direction to build up its asset portfolio and strengthen its leasing segments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
